yeah so so last night
i i noticed that my mind was turning to
a a frame of making sense
of the the thing that
is sometimes referred to as culture ward
2.
there's a phenomenon in the context of
that phenomenon there's of course lots
of different things that are going on
and one way of naming it has been
culture war 2.0
and it has a lot of attention i mean i
think a lot of people
maybe most people um certainly most
people involved in social media
um have a sense of attending to it a
sense of concern
a sense that there's a problem there um
maybe even more than just a little bit
of like a big problem like a sense of
like something bad is happening
and also not only do i not have a sense
of what to do about it but i have a
distinct felt sense that nobody does
like this like a therefore a poor tent
that will just get worse
right which leads i think oftentimes to
to kind of two or three strategies right
one strategy is
just helplessness and hopelessness the
second strategy which is just kind of
that
with higher agency which would be kind
of cynicism and
you know participation in the in the
progressive badness by virtue of making
small local wins
yeah right would they say like
millennials won't own
any properties so then they could do his
own people online like that kind of a
sensibility
and then the third of course is even
that is the worst which is
highly strategic uh local games
so in the context of this how do i
actually grab and make you know
steal or take territory for myself which
of course is
pervasive among the most engented groups
so
what i was thinking about was i think i
was thinking i'm not sure what the
orient what the origin was but
greg's the the paper greg sent me
actually
which was this russian mathematician who
was taking multiple different
uh data points like different people who
had done data points similar to the one
that kurzweil based his curves on
right right um but but very distinctly
from actually different cultures and
different languages and so for very
different models
but as it turns out all very similar
curves and the russian mathematicians
did in fact
i can give you one formula that
describes all of them
um and the deeper point was
the the thing that's under investigation
the thing that's changing in time
is is actually the rate of paradigm
shifts
so the paradigm a particular phase
transition in
quality at the end of emergence of
quality
um are happening faster and faster
they're happening closer and closer
together
so the the thing that i was thinking
about was like okay one frame that we
might use to explain what's happening
is something like you know the
singularity is happening it's just
unevenly distributed
that what we're seeing as culture war
is actually just the high the the
the specific response
of structures psychological structures
political structures
in the context of um
this kind of a warping or a shaping i
think something will seem like a tornado
like a
a vortex of change that
is happening differentially so it's
happening in different places at
different rates so for example one of
the reasons why
um say like the west coast of the us
or the big cities um happen to be hot
spots of
these super intense culture war type
forces
in this frame is in fact actually
because
that's where the effect of the
singularity is at its most
advanced like that's where it's
happening the most
um so are you using singularity in the
kurzweil sense
well i mean i'm using it in the sense of
this particular russian
theorist so it has to do with something
like an accelerating rate of change
in the in this in the paradigmatic sense
so
uh deep change and deep change now
happening at a rate that is
inside uh our psychological capacity to
respond so by the time we've actually
begun to re-cohere some kind of
paradigm the paradigm itself is actually
shifting right so the
the story the story that this guy tells
um is
well i'll superimpose it the story tells
zooming in on like the last thousand
years
um or i guess post bronze age um
after the after the post bronze age
collapse after the
that dark age um i guess the axial age
was
the invention of paradigmatic mind a
particular mind that had a capacity to
generate
models largely in the propositional
layer to
coordinate behavior across large
populations by using these models
and then mechanisms for disseminating it
and holding the models as having
a certain level of uh ideological
integrity
okay so so formal meaning structures uh
and then and then it's a
a time frame a period of time where the
paradigms would
s curve right they would begin the
process of formation they would actually
become relatively effective they would
manifest as
emergent practical capacities in reality
which would show up in terms of
economy and military and things like
that which would then lead to expansive
civilizations uh then they would reach
the the nadir of the paradigm's own
efficacy
uh with anomaly i'm doing kind of
tainter and coon at the same time
yeah yeah i get it um anomalies would
start getting thrown you would start
getting
decreasing returns on complicatedness et
cetera
and then you would have some kind of a
of a collapse both at the level of
psychology
meaning our meaning making structures
are becoming ineffective
and the level of economy and military
and then you would have some new
paradigm emerge
um and the singularity hypothesis
proposes that this is actually something
which is happening more rapidly
as you go like a thousand years and then
500 years and now 250 i'm just using
havoc but it's not that's not the actual
curve and the point is that the
the if you think about the the
developmental
capacity of homo sapiens right it's very
much embedded in in
in generational cycles meaning that uh
eight-year-olds can divorce can develop
a paradigm much more rapidly than
80-year-olds
or can adapt to a new paradigm more
rapidly so there's like a rate limiter
of as long as the rate of change of
paradigms is happening
outside outside of that rate you know
the boomers you remember the generation
gap
yeah the boomers are literally
developmentally responding to a
completely different
paradigm than their parents so it was
that their parents you know were
developmentally in paradigm eight
and boomers were actually
developmentally in paradigm nine because
the paradigm had shifted
inside that that art within the lasting
within that 50 year period
um but the boomers were in fact in some
sense well adapted
to the paradigm in which they were in
the paradigm itself you know
suffers from this from change and cooney
and problems but the boomers are well
adapted to it
but by the time you start getting into
the 70s what happens is that
in inside a developmental arc like the
generation x is characterized by kind of
like having a half step
so the mid-century paradigm was already
broken by the time that we were
coming of age but a new paradigm hadn't
yet shifted so we were caught
but then with the millennials again in
this theory what happens to the
millennials is
as they show up in a paradigm you know
they develop into a paradigm by the time
they're you know 14
that paradigm is already collapsing and
by the time they're 28
the next paradigm is already collapsing
so now inside the psychological
developmental space of a single human
life
if you start getting paradigm shifts
happening at that rate that's a
completely different game
so you've got a you know a game where
the periodic structure has a set of
characteristic problems having to do
with tantrums
and whatnot but then you've got another
game or another
set of characteristics that matter that
you when when the when a paradigm shift
is happening
inside four generations
so that you've got a generation gap that
creates a a
a dynamic then when it's happening
inside a single human
psychological developmental time frame
that's another dynamic
and so the proposition would be
something like one of the
so to explain like a phenomenal
explanation from one of the things we're
seeing is
i have like these fingers of of
instability like if i have a field
effective like
what's like a think of like a science
fiction movie where
you know over there time is actually
moving faster than over there
and so in certain places like certain
places are literally
uh because of the
well i don't talk about that just yet
but for reasons um
are are more immersed in a
uh paradigm evolution or paradigm
dynamics
that are operating at a currently at a
higher rate and so
you know something like say some areas
in silicon valley are operating at a
pace where
they're already on the other side of a
particular paradigm change where say
like kansas
isn't so you've got the generation gap
between them
but and also more importantly because
the different the rate of change is
higher you've actually got a breakdown
in mind to break down
the psychology that is on the premise on
the notion of having a paradigm to run
at all
um so that was the thinking
and just to bring it back around to the
original proposal the original proposal
is
that the culture wars are symptomatic of
the fact
that these rates of paradigmatic change
are not evenly distributed
is that the idea yeah exactly and in
some sense it's it's
we're actually perceiving them as
culture wars
but in fact they're not there's a better
way to understand what's actually
happening is that the
the choices that are showing up like
what's actually going on
is literally just a local response to
the level of
paradigm change that's going on in your
environment
um that's more it's a more uh how do i
say this right like
imagine i have a uh
a bunch of iron filings and i noticed
that the iron filings are moving
and so i i i sort of look at them and
say well the iron filings are moving for
reasons having to do with the iron
violence
and somebody else comes along and says
no i've actually got a magnet under the
table
right so yeah what you're saying is uh
to use sort of uh
experimental lingo is i've seen you
the people in the culture wars think
there's a causal relationship
uh but there's act but it's only a
correlation and there's an underlying
third variable
yeah that's right both of them so it's
not the filings are not
impacting on each other it only looks
that way it's because of the magnet
underneath where the magnet is
the paradigmatic chain is that is that
yeah more specifically the rate the rate
of the paramedic change
and and and the and the implications of
a rate of paradigmatic change that's now
happening
inside the capacity of minds
the way that our psychological coherence
systems operates
that creates the paradigmatic mind is no
longer able to actually respond to its
own context
so the context is changing faster than
the mind's ability to generate this
particular form of response to context
okay that sounds that's a really
interesting proposal it's kind of like
yeah we're sort of facing perpetual
future shock
of you know tougher's notion yeah there
but it's not equally distributed now
what's the main explanation for why the
distribution isn't equal does it have to
do something like with
access to technology um
you know population density what kind of
variables
are would account for uh the
heterogeneous distribution
of the future shock um i would say
there's probably three
um so and i think it's pretty
straightforward actually so
what i would say is it's something like
um
i think we do a very simple model which
looks at it
in the in the language of computation
right in information processing sure and
so the notion is
and and searching the the search for
the search of the space of dj is
impossible right and so
so change happens as a consequence of a
combination between
the space of the adjacent possible the
search through that space of the
adjacent possible
and then the apparently somewhat
stochastic discovery of
real uh things that are enduring inside
the space it then
generates the new space right so that's
like that's the move you go from
what we have the adjacent possible you
find things the adjacent possible to
create new reality
that new reality now becomes the new
reality and then you kind of iterate
okay so that's the that's the base
now the notion is that you can define
the the key characteristic
is the the search through the adjacent
possible what's the search algorithm
the search algorithm of course is
distributed cognition right right
recognition is governed by cognition i.e
each individual mind and its current
capacity to operate in a particular
fashion so
a mind that has the capacity to do
symbolic compression at a very high
level and in fact
engage in trans symbolic translations
like we like we often do yeah yeah like
we just did in that moment
um has a higher facility for distributed
cognition than a mind that doesn't
that has doesn't have that capacity and
i think might be typological certain
neurologies may be affordable to that
and also
uh educational certain uh techniques and
practices just
in that direction obviously if you've
you know done a lot of studying in
higher mathematics
that's one of the techniques empire
mathematics is precisely that
software does a very similar thing so
different capacities in particular minds
then of course you've got the specific
relationality between those months which
will be governed largely by their um
embodied relationships so population
density and
and the great sort you know silicon
valley happened to have become an
attractor for particular typologies with
particular experiences and capacities
and put them into close proximity
physically
and then of course you have social media
right and so uh presencing and
interacting in in telecommunications
which which enables this sort of weirdly
dysfunctional disembodied but
very high-end metcalf interaction in
abstract space
so if i have that i basically have
created a search algorithm of the
adjacent possible
governed by from the bottom up governed
by the
the relevance realization mechanism of
each individual human
right and by the topology of the
search system itself yeah i get that
right um and that's unevenly distributed
and so what ends up happening is that
the propagation of the things that are
extracted from the adjacent possible
has some almost like uh it moves
at the very least it moves at the speed
of light and so uh
but in fact he practically was a lot
slower than that and so it emerges in
some location it propagates through that
location
but its propagation through that
location actually changes
the search capacity in the area through
which it is propagated right so if
you're closer to
um open ai you know if you're if you're
closer to open air meaning
you actually have the capacity to use
the technology
you're closer right where somebody has
the capacity to like be aware of it is
further than you but close it up as
somebody who's not even heard of it
can't even make sense it's further away
so if you're closer to to open and gpt
three
you're now like one more step further in
terms of the search algorithm of
actually
because that's part of the invention of
gpt3 or more specifically it's
its presence in the world is a result as
an expansion in the json possible
right a big chunk of the adjacent
possible is realized coherent
and our reality has just changed if
you're closer to it you have access to
it
and you're by the way just by the very
nature of being closer to it you're in a
social field of relationships that are
all closer to it
and therefore are already playing in a
different playing field of a different
context
and a big part of that context is
simultaneously more potential
more adjacent possible and a more
sophisticated or more
higher bandwidth distributed cognition
using those tools on themselves
right so you get that recursive that
recursion
begins to pull my that area and the
people who are in that location
further in a certain like further down
the rabbit hole
of possibility right subject to the
various constraints
of things like
the necessity to maintain some level of
continuity with other
elements in the social group at the end
of the day
and this is where we then show us having
culture wars yeah
right so that's that was very helpful
i'm trying to think about i'm trying to
map
especially the one i'm more familiar
with the kunian sense of paradigm into
what you're saying here
we're talking about parasitic shift
because it's it seems to me that
that there's something in there that has
to do with the coordination between
those levels
the individual cognition the distributed
cognition and
uh the cyber enhanced cognition
you know all the enhanced relevance
realization which is
basically what's going on here in
various configurations so i mean kuhn's
idea is that's exactly what a paradigm
was right a paradigm gives us
it gives us uh because
the search is neither arbitrary because
it'll be combinatorial explosive
or algorithmic because that would be
exhaustive and then combinatorially
explosive
right we we what we get are we get
exemplars
that give us uh sort of constellation of
heuristics
so we get the we get the exemplar
experiment
we get the exemplar scientific question
right and then we get the exemplar
theorist and then though that
constellation of exemplars
gives us this sort of toolkit for
managing the relevance realization and
there it's ultimately heuristic and
eventually over time it breaks down
so what i'm trying to when i'm trying to
fit them into the picture here is
like like what so what do you mean more
precisely by a paradigmatic shift
do you mean something like analogous to
cune
that are the the set of exemplars that
we use
as a source of heuristics
for trying to deal with the new search
through the search base is ultimately
changing so
people are more and more rapidly
appealing to
different paradigmatic individuals
paradigmatic
problems right so let me let me see if i
can provide a more fundamental language
let's see let's see if i can if we can
do it because we can and it gets really
interesting
um i'm pretty sure this is i'm making
this up
so uh well that's often that's often a
very been a very successful strategy for
you
yes which is why i keep doing it all
right so so here's the thing um
as you said you've got these kind of
these challenges of combinatorial
explosion because this this
that vastness and vastness of territory
and what i'm going to say is
what i would propose is that the the
language of the space
the possibility space inside the
adjacent possible
um is the
is the problem of the combinatorial
explosion right so the the
n inside the possibility space the
adjacent possible is super large
right or extraordinarily large
particularly now
right by the way not infinite but just
very very very very large
yeah yeah um and and so the the the
challenge
to use the language we just are using of
the search
um is to
use this constellation of heuristics and
exemplars
which if i in my mind what i'm seeing is
is that is that i'm engaging in
a what's the right it's again i'm
i'm actually imposing a certain kind of
um my modification to the shape of the
possibility space
to effectively print pardon me there's
soft constraints the exemplar gives you
sets of
construction right and i'm creating
low-hanging fruit
right i'm i'm using that mechanism to
generate
low-hanging fruit okay
which then means that i can actually
reach them using my resources using
using the the finite capacity for search
that i can actually do
i do two moves right the paradigm of the
paradigm does is it creates
a constraint landscape a constraint on
my search which is to say that it
it does the job of surfacing low-hanging
fruit
and then of course i actually harvest
the hanging fruit okay so that's that's
like the deeper i think the deeper
language
um which describes the phenomenon and so
then
what happens in the context of a
paradigm shift
is at the level of those constraints
which is to say that
any given paradigm is
uh how do i say this
it the the the constraints constraints
right so so while it while it surfaces
certain things it
it uh moves other things further away
every heuristic is a bias
every heuristic is a bias there you go
thank you and so what happens is that
to say a paradigm shift all we're
talking about is we're actually you know
modulating
the set of constraints which um
generates a different exposure to
certain areas territories of the
landscape
and in particular in in the consequence
of a real change in the possibility
space
and a real change in our searching
capacity right so
you know some particular thing we use a
very concrete example like
the laser which you were never going to
find before quantum mechanics because
the
the heuristic the heuristics of the even
general relativity but certainly
of newtonian physics the distance to
to laser through just sort of
engineering trial and error
was effectively infinite sure and
the level of distributed cognition in
was you know relatively tiny in in
comparison to this to the space
and so then the the innovation of
quantum mechanics
uh you know suddenly radically shifts
the the surface area of the possibility
space
moving laser much closer to the surface
like bubbling up this sort of diamond
from the
from the haystack needle the needle
surface from the haystack
and then of course these the set of
telecommunications and urban
environments and educational processes
that
meaningfully upgraded our distributed
cognition by the time you get into the
1930s and 40s
you get a cross-function that actually
breaches the laser as is now available
within the
landscape right um and
and of course the the proposition is
that these constraints
and these biases are biases that are
happening in all different levels of
distributed cognition like you're
talking about so
you know as an individual i'm you know
go ahead
i was going to say they have to be
shared and coordinated so part of what
i'm
seeing i'm sorry to interrupt but i just
want to make sure i'm getting it
a paradigm is something like an
overarching
met a set of medic constraints that
coordinate right they curate and
coordinate the strip the constraints at
various levels
so that they're operating in some
fashion so you're getting some
optimization on
your harvesting exactly exactly
particularly what they do is they
radically reduce the communications
cross that enables distributed cognition
to be functional
right if you're operating with an
entirely different set of axioms a
different set of constraints than i am
then what happens is the cost of simply
coming into the point where our
coordination is possible at all
is super hot but it's very very heavy
and so what happens is what the paradigm
does is it simplifies coordination costs
and it enables a you know a physicist in
germany to have a conversation with a
physicist in spain
um and they're more that's on the same
page where they have a whole a
whole set of set of a huge set of
assumptions they're sitting on top of
and they're just working on the very
the top level um so it has the bad
advantage
it radically upgrades our distributed
cognition
in effectiveness you probably have much
better language for
this it's basically an optimization
process right it enables us to be
extremely effective at searching using
it
using the space that has been bound by
those constraints
yeah right but it's also a bit of
closure it closes that space so that you
enter and enter into kind of like a
thermodynamic problem
yeah that's what it's going to say so
don't don't
i mean the the the functionality of the
heuristic is also
um you know the the self-deceptive
aspect to it
in that right we get locked into we're
biased
and if you're if we're optimizing
is are you suggesting that something
like um
the rate at which we hit so let's go
back to your harvesting metaphor because
it's helpful here
right so initially you know my
standard economic model i put in so much
effort and the low the low-hanging fruit
means with little effort i get it
the problem is if i if i harvest the low
if i if i can harvest the low-hanging
fruit
faster and faster i hit diminishing
returns
faster and faster is that the idea
that's exactly what happens so remember
because you've got two things going on
simultaneously one is the constraints
actually
surface a new landscape that has low
hanging fruit
the second is it also gives rise to a
uh a set of low-hanging fruit in the
domain of the of distributed cognition
right right so in so i've got a
different i've got two s curves that are
happening simultaneously
one is the rate at which i'm harvesting
low-hanging fruit in the domain of
distributed cognition
and turning that into effectiveness in
under this set of constraints right so
so when i move to new paradigm
i kind of like have a whole lot of new
low-hanging fruit and a new
potential distributed cognition but i'm
just kind of done
because we're having to we're kind of
starting over at kindergarten in this
new distributed cognition model
um but but i can i can get the lowest
singing fruit even at a low level
distributed cognition
but as i harvest them they get harder
but i'm also simultaneously getting
smarter in my new distributed cognition
capacity
so there's kind of this really
interesting feedback curve between the
degree the rate at which
i'm i'm making the problem of finding
fruit harder by harvesting the lowest
hanging ones and getting up
you know whatever the topology that
looks like and the rate at which i'm
actually harvesting the specific living
fruit and integrating them into
improving cognition which is going to
have an s curve
right and so i get this tainter now it's
kind of now we get we flip back to
tainter
i get a process of crossover where my
rate of advance in distributed cognition
is slowing down
and also my rate of the degree of
difficulty of harvesting is continuing
to go up right so there's a crossover
point where that
that s-curve in a uh
right in a paradigm is when i've still
got a pretty sizable number of
low-hanging fruit but i'm getting really
good at harvesting them
right right right then i'm actually
reaching diminishing returns on
harvesting
but now that all the food are hard hard
to get now things get really expensive
really fast
and now i'm kind of the tail end of the
paradigm but um
i've made a huge investment so i've got
a degree of change
you know i'm hyper my distributed
cognition is extremely effective
um relative to any location next to it
so any move in terms of sort of abstract
effectiveness
sorry it's a hill climbing valley
crossing exercise right i've reached the
top of
a local hill in the context of the set
of constraints defined by the paradigm
right right right any move is perceived
as a down a downward movement
and that hill yeah it keeps you trapped
in attracting the local minimum
okay and so
there's a sense in which the inaudible
it's interesting because the anomalies
then
are are are our evidence right so in the
cuny sense the anomalies are just
evidence
that your particular paradigm can't
account for a certain amount of data
but you've also got if i'm following
your argument correctly
the anomalies as the anomalies start to
pile up that's also a marker
that you're you're hitting this
crossover point right that you're
hitting the point where
um the ability to improve
um um our ability to deal with
diminishing returns is it's
self-diminishing
right uh and so at some point we can't
we can't
we can't improve how we harvest the
higher hanging fruit fast enough
for how high the food is getting right
that way
right right yeah and um and the
anomalies actually show
as having a positive value because they
provide the um
sort of subtle vague but orienting basis
for
what a shift might look like right so
we're not operating in complete
randomness it's like okay well there's a
whole bunch of open questions
that inside the bias the set of biases
and constraints that i'm operating i
can't actually give good answers
but they're questions they're real
things they're things out there in the
world
and so it gives you it's actually a very
interesting handoff
um so then you have remember going back
to neuroplasticity
right as you know right as you and i
know all too well as you reach certain
developmental stages as a human being
your uh your willingness and capacity
to kind of in at the neurological level
and also at the motivational level um
god even at the social level
uh that is of course to to engage in
that level of change goes
down this is the eric weinstein i think
you know keeps calling out but can't
quite get over the threshold which is
you know in the contemporary context um
everybody who's in charge of all the
institutions
is at a you know at the very tail end of
an escrow
so the intrinsic conservativism
is kind of being reinforced to all three
levels right the individual
is incapable of actually shifting
at a neurological level the degree of
change necessary to actually unload
those constraints and move to new ones
is very high sort of neural cognitive
level
they're also unwilling to shift because
such a shift is hard and they don't
they don't have the level of youthful
enthusiasm to go into that kind of an
adventure
and sociologically it implies for sure
a reduction of their local authority and
influence
this is kind of funny i can actually
take the influence piece from from
greg's stuff
way down right they're no longer like
the master of this domain just another
schmuck trying to figure out how to make
it in this
new space um and of course that also has
the direct
interpersonal like the actual reality of
the people who they know
are positioned just like this just like
a game theoretic and i'm not gonna
like come on dude don't go into the new
paradigm you're gonna fuck things up for
everybody
i'm not going to need a pair of
everybody kind of like holds in place
um and that's like that that very last
piece it's almost like this um
it feels like it's like the second
decision point on the tainter curve
which is really interesting because
actually correlates with the second
decision point that
carol quigley talks about his book the
evolution of civilizations
which is basically like you get a uh
a second derivative deceleration
so the rate of change is slowing down in
your s curve
is the first decision point and that's
where things actually are the most
meaningful if you make the choice there
to
shift you're you're okay but you also
are giving up the golden age
of maximum excel maximum extraction
second decision point is when the actual
um
when velocity is going down right right
right you've got acceleration is
decreasing velocity is decreasing your
different decision points
um you know so when you're actually in a
recession as opposed to just a
slower and slower growth um
why did i say that oh yeah probably
being part of the challenge here has to
do with the
because there's kind of a stickiness
there's a
a lack of fluidity uh an intrinsic
conservativism
in in the nature of the paradigmatic
model itself right the way that it
grows and extends and the way it extends
by the way both into the human
psychological
and into the institutional
massive investments in institutional
fabric i remember talking about it in
the context of um
like just oil as a function yeah i
remember that yeah
if you just look at like the amount of
investment in say like the educational
infrastructure of teaching this huge
population of people how to run and
operate the technology and institutions
of the oil industry at the financial
level at the
mining level the technical level and to
shift away from oil
obsoletes that entire kind of capital
investment
and obsoletes the capital of the meta
like the deeper capital investment in
the underlying infrastructure that
produces that as you've got all these
things that are kind of massively
invested
stock versus flow on on x
and so what happens is that the
counterweight the the
pressure for change the number of
anomalies that are now showing up in all
these different ways like there's
anomalies that are showing up in terms
of
questions that we can't answer using the
model structures that we operate in but
also anomalies that are showing up in
terms of um
like conflicts that happen between
institutions
like emergent institutions and classical
institutions or
um psychological dissonance between
different
identity structures like these are all
the novels so if they're happening
throughout the entire system dynamic
um you get stronger and stronger and
stronger and it kind of breaks an
elegant this is one of the problems with
the paratrooper models it tends it tends
to
not almost never break elegantly
it almost never just says okay cool it's
time to you know hand off the keys to
the next generation
so this is this is that point i was
trying to make about generations is that
when paradigm shifts happened over a
period of time
or there actually was a sort of natural
human
clock you know the the victorians as
they got
you know past a certain age the you know
the young
kind of mid-century types they could
just kind of like take over
and they would be operating in in a
different
uh set of sensibilities and so the
natural transition
from you know elder to to younger
worked but when the paradigm change is
actually happening inside that cycle
then you don't have any natural
transition like there's nothing that
enables it to happen
um or so sorry that
that fluid mechanism for transfer
doesn't happen so now the transfer
actually has to be even harder
right i mean that's kuhn's idea that uh
you paradigm shift often just works by
waiting for the old guys to die
um but um right and now if you have like
three paradigm shifts happening inside a
single person's life
what happens yeah you can so so the
you see the culture wars now what i'm
trying to get at
now is there's two possible ways
interpreting this is the other culture
wars
are you saying that various groups are
on different places on the sort of
the curve of the paradigm shift or are
you saying that all of the groups
share certain characteristics of trying
to retreat into a kind of
over stabilization function through
tribal identity etc etc
right both okay yes exactly
and that's that's why it's challenging i
said well it's challenging in both cases
and the fact that it's both is why it's
really challenging to get a hold of
um and so um
yeah let's just focus on the second part
so i think a video went around a little
bit about mcluhan actually talking about
how when you hit a certain level of
information overwhelmed
we default to simple pattern recognition
right so we've got a whole bunch of
basic strategies of how to deal with
certain levels of information
overwhelmed as you said like you default
to
try things have to get simpler you just
can't you can't deal so
things get simpler and so i'm gonna
problematize this
in in like three ways now so
the the first way is okay we've kind of
reached
uh information overwhelm which is to say
that the velocity
and and magnitude of anomalies has
reached a point
where our ordinary mechanisms of
ignoring them and
rationalizing in the context of the
paradigm
i can no longer continue to bullshit
myself enough to just continue to slog
through things
yeah so then what happens is i start
kicking into this next mode right so the
basic mode
is my paradigm is working pretty well
and anomalies i just kind of ignore and
proceed forward 19 1980s in america
all right model so that when that starts
to
break down then i have to shift to model
2. model 2 is where i start going
click and i drop into some sort of more
basic strategy
now of course this is this is part of
what drives the culture of course is
that
people who maybe were compatible inside
a paradigm
may have very different more simple
strategies exactly exactly
say drop out yeah local idiosyncratic
histories are going to be magnified when
you drop out of a shared paradigm
so people are going to default to more
primitive earlier
forms within their own you know local
developmental trajectories so this
worked
and so when they when they when they
when they do the regression strategy
because
psychologically that's what it is it's a
regressive strategy right
when you know if you grew up somewhere
else than i did and et cetera when we
regress we're going to
it's going to tend to highlight our
differences it's going to differentiate
us
in a powerful way and it's also at the
same time going to reduce our cognitive
flexibility to manage those difference
because we're moving to more
scarcity mentality right yeah and it's
funny because
also in exactly that context more
regressive strategies
happen to be more oriented around more
presenting of scarcity
yes the notion of can't we all get along
is a relatively modern
innovation the notion of like fuck you
is a law it's been around a lot longer
um so that so since that second level
gets very you know
is kind of like a good solid chunk of
okay problematization but then i want to
introduce that third level which is that
you know it's
actually happening it's unevenly
distributed so you actually have a
uh like a jerk so it's not just velocity
accelerations velocity acceleration and
jerk
so the actual rate of change um is
different in different locations and so
uh this creates all kinds of weird
uh impedance uh at even at the level of
response
so there may actually it's quite likely
actually that many people are operating
in
like a third response mode you know if
you can't deal with with the vote with
the
volume or the you get information
overwhelmed right you you operate one
way
but if in fact the the that set of
default modes are themselves breaking
because the rate of change is actually
accelerating beyond
anything that any structure's ever dealt
with which is the reality that's what's
actually happening
then you've got a completely different
thing going on um
and you you so that the regression is
kind of regressive acceleration i
suppose is
right um and differential regressive
acceleration so it's almost like one of
these crazy sci-fi movies where you've
got like
cavemen sitting you know right next to
like 1950s people and like people from
the future they're all kind of like
there's a
show about that right a book a book that
had like a river
and the river had this weird like
conjunction yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah um and that's uh i think
that's that's
like an interesting frame to be thinking
about what's going on
um okay so the idea is
let me see i get this uh we get the
regression in which locks people down
and they they then right that's
happening but they're
also being locked at different places on
the time river
right and so not only are they locked
they're
also incommensurably placed on the prime
river
is that yeah something like that yeah
and so it's like
if you think about it in terms of the
way that a black hole works where
um if i'm on the other side of the event
horizon communication is impossible
because
light actually can't you know move
across it
it's a little bit like that right where
if we were all sort of
if we were all changing at roughly the
same rate then there would be some way
of generating effectively a meta
protocol
that could try to find something that
was
uh able to be communicated horizontally
at that rate
but if what's happening is we're
actually all changing at different rates
it's kind of like um you're looking at a
stick in the water
and trying to grab it yeah yeah there's
actually a warp
so you know i say x but if you're
actually basically operating a different
time signature that i'm operating in
then you know i i have to actually begin
to learn
is there is there enough regularity at
all is there enough constancy at all
to actually be able to kind of have
coherence
work in communication can we communicate
or is there like a redshift doppler kind
of thing going on
between between us where there's um
so much i guess delta
so much change to that yeah so much
distortion
that the the communication well one
possibility is communication is
impossible right in which case you would
actually have effectively a speciation
effect it would be some sort of
shift like a pulling away literally just
begin the process of something that is
increasingly not part of something else
yeah that's plausible i think there's
many people who actually have thought
about that as something that has been
happening and you say okay well that
would be a natural consequence
um and okay and so what happens is you
have this weird
um how do i say this like it's like a
viscosity challenge where
the front end god this language is rough
so what i'm trying to say is like if i
happen to be a guy working on ai
in silicon valley some part of me is
like the front end of something right
next to the edge of the black hole
right the part of me that is right at
the bleeding edge of of ai
is like right at the event horizon it's
like you haven't like there's a
stretching effect
yeah but i also like buy food and
you know walk around and see buildings
right
and interact with just people that are
around me
um maybe right undercover less and less
bizarrely enough
um so i have something else another
another aspect of my experience and the
aspect to my identity and
my relationships are operating in this
other boat right so that's that's
another piece right it's like the
stretching it's not just unevenly
distributed in terms of geography it's
actually unevenly distributed in terms
of identity and cognition and psychology
and that stretching piece i think is
another key element
like to think about um
yeah and maybe to make it a kind of a
simple science fiction story
just think what happens so let me assume
that elon musk is telling the truth
about what he's doing with neural ways
so what it can do is as reported
right no no more no less and i don't
know if that's true right he could be
totally lying and it can't do any of it
anything else be totally lying and it's
actually way ahead of that he's just
kind of giving us the their
adopted piece of it even then it's
massive right
other than the most recent thing he
talked about was how like they expect to
soon be able to stream music directly to
your brain
and so that level of intimacy but i just
i it's
but that's we'll talk about that maybe
another time me too
but let's just as a simple kind of
science fiction example
there's like these as soon as somebody
actually does the neural lace thing
right and so we can that's very concrete
but the point is that that's already
happening
in less that's obvious ways yeah yeah i
get that yeah for sure i mean we're
doing it right now
yeah we're doing it right now and
we could actually if we publish this and
we look at the comments
we'll actually see that kind of
stretching or
differential right some people will just
like bounce the fuck off
everything they just said would be so
you know whatever
and then their response will be whatever
regressive strategy happens to be their
local
location right which you know is like 50
that i've seen so far
so it's getting harder and harder
to get a common denature a common
denominator of quality
we can never have the beetles again so
the thing about the beatles
is right they were at that point where
they tapped into you know that the
broadcasting ability and and the you
know
the the ability to stamp out final
records but
right they're at that point where they
could they could create a
something analogous to a paradigm
popular culture
we can never have the beatles again and
that's not because there aren't talented
people out there
it's because the proliferation of genres
right is just
is accelerated it's like a protestantism
it's it right it's
it's proliferating and proliferating and
what you get i mean i i notice it myself
is i'm now stuck in time with it come
when it comes to popular music
no not because not because i'm a luddite
or anything like that
it's just i think i can't keep up and
not only can i can't keep up
because we have to remember there's this
is not a contradiction
there is more information out there but
it's also more impoverished
it's less diagnostic like if you're
around in the time of the beatles there
was a chance that
all of the genres could it could reach
you
the genres can't all reach me now right
no right no matter how much they pump
out
right right there's genres i don't know
up there now and you know i see i see i
see my kids and
you know you know and my partner's kids
and those
what i don't even know what that is i
don't even know who that is
right and then it's not and at first i
think
well is it because i'm just i'm like i'm
like turning into my parents
part of it's that uh you know but the
part of it is what we're talking about
here no you know it's not like i've
encountered these genres like my parents
did and then rejected them
they are not even on my radar that's the
that's the me that's the thing to me
that's
paradoxical i've been trying to get this
across to some of my students
that we have simultaneously and i think
maybe daniel
schmeichenberg is trying to get this
right we have simultaneously
way more information but there's there's
sense in which each piece of information
is less diagnostically valuable because
it can't it
is not as diagnostic it doesn't it
doesn't rule out as many alternatives
as clearly and as effectively because it
gets overwhelmed
by the sea of information it's in it's
also corrupted
that the signal is corrupted because of
the all of the competition do you
understand what i'm trying to do yeah
yeah yeah absolutely
well uh well i'm kind of not trying to
do the thing right so the
the point is so what we're just talking
about
i noticed like a bunch of connections to
previous conversations that we
individually and collectively have had
is something along the lines of
we've reached the limits of a particular
um fundamental mode of being in relation
of
distributed cognition which is to say of
being in relationship with dj is
impossible which is what you're
describing because
um each genre in some sense is a it's a
particular
mode of distributed cognition particular
meta node
that is exploring the possibility space
within a particular set of constraints
in music space
right that's exactly that's what that's
what i'm intending to analogy
and your point is that uh the graph is
no longer connected
meaning that the the propagation uh
in i don't know like genre n
uh isn't connected like it's actually
not connected what's going on over here
in genre m
and in some sense they're actually we
might imagine actually moving apart
further
so that like the light cone they may
never connect
yeah proliferation of genres genres
because
they are biased based the genres also
isolate each like like if i have more
piercing genres right and if i get more
and more genres between them
that's that's an accelerating isolation
function because the
number of bias thresholds i have to
cross to get that information
is also going up exactly so to put it
very specifically so the
the efficiency of the advantage of the
paradigm has
comes with the concomitant cost which is
it radically reduces coordinating costs
inside the paradigm
it radically increases coordinating
cross
coordination costs outside of or between
paradigms
right so if you are in the same paradigm
it becomes relatively easy for us to
coordinate
before actually operating outside of
paradigms if you're in a different
paradigm than me
we're almost impeachable you know
the the amount of delta because the
whole point because
the paradigm is collaborative it's a
distributed cognition so it's actually
being the innovation the paradigm is
being held in many many many many many
different minds
no given mind can actually go through
and say like okay i can hold the whole
of my paradigm and so i can translate to
the whole of your paradigm that's not
starter
so what happens of course is that as the
genres themselves actually become
paradigms
unto themselves and are exploring
musical space
unto themselves the interoperability
cost between them
is actually going up and so actually i
experienced this myself like i
would listen to my daughters play music
um and we and we're not like
in tight sync right so they'll kind of
they'll show up and they they will have
drifted the way they
drift and they'll play music and i'll
listen to it going
you know wow i actually have a very hard
time
knowing what's going on there i can kind
of i can i can hear actually
it's funny the way my mind works i can
actually hear a lot of the evolutionary
history
like oh that particular move that
particular
set of sounds like i remember hearing
that as certain other sounds i could
hear how this particular musician was
a brico lot you know greek lodging but
the technique and the aesthetic
that leads to this actually coming
together as a kind of music and by the
way even the tools
um i'm not i i don't i don't really i
don't connect to and so
whatever's going on there it's very
difficult for me to be part of that flow
in lineage and the distance is getting
further and further
um so so at some point
i mean sorry this this might sound like
a pedantic point but
it's a conceptual point i mean if it
fragments to that point
isn't i mean the whole point about a
paradigm is it's supposed to
give an overarching integration i mean
are we getting to a place
where paradigms are now impossible
because there has been so
much the metaphor that's running around
in my mind is how
you know sexual selection can so you
know niche construct you
so that you actually stop to be via you
stop being viable in terms of natural
selection
right you know the peacock's tail is the
classic example
yeah right that's a dead right um
and so like are we getting to the place
where paradigms
are not possible but if that's the case
then what we're getting is variation
without without selection right
yes okay so and there's
like i think this is another way of
saying the thing that i keep saying
which is that
there's like a bifurcation event you
know so the the regressive move
continues to have to regress to find
some
checksum against which selection finally
occurs
yeah okay that generally speaking will
show but the energetic domain
you know at the end of the day if i
cannot communicate with you in any way
linguistically i can definitely punch
you in the face
yes right and so that's what i meant
about you
the quality of the common denominator is
going to continue to drop
because right the trying to get what can
cross all that fragmentation
is going to have to go into something um
that
is yeah i guess sort of
that has been preserved the longest
through through the evolutionary process
or something like that
right exactly preserve the longest the
evolutionary process exactly
it's the most basic or most primitive i
guess the
longest um and then and and or right
that's
this direction and then you've got this
direction right and it's funny because i
think we started this conversation
sort of noticing that we're gonna be
talking with greg soon
and i'm seeing a lot of the things that
he and i talked about coming back which
is great greg enriquez henry yeah
yeah sorry to make it more uh uh
explicit
um so so john gregon and i are going to
have a conversation
soon a week and john and i were just
talking about some of
our our encounters with greg's stuff and
so you know
the last time that he and i talked i
don't know if we shared so
i apologize if we did or didn't um
was that the
what does he call it he calls it but
there's like the
the series of cones that are nested in
each other and at the surface area
yeah and there's a point at which
there's a juncture between
one level and the next level and you
know his proposition is that what we're
witnessing is at the juncture of the
culture level as it
you know gives rise to the next level
and the point is that
there's a the thing that's on the upside
is now i can name it
transparadigmatic right and what does
that mean
uh well that means something
that has the capacity to
enable selection enable interoperability
enable
communication relationship um
in a context of um also enabling
um
niches or or
not diversity what was it
diversification yeah speciation
um and so it's like it is a it's a meta
culture the whole point is that it can't
be of the same sort
as paradigm and and the distributed
cognition can't be of the same sort as
the distributed cognition that operates
in paradigm space
so we can we can kind of do the negative
space like the negative space is
all this stuff not it right and and a
little bit of the positive space it has
to be able to do these sorts of things
and then that ink that thing right there
like figuring out how to do that
that ends up being a lot of what you and
me and john are
that's a big a good description of the
space that we're trying to figure out
is yeah what's this trans-paradigmatic
uh metaculture right that has the
ability to maintain
interoperability communicability
capacity to be in relationship and
therefore selection that is not
primitive selection but at a much higher
level um
while of course realizing the fact that
um
in that context the notion of paradigm
has now become
uh it's a lot it's like happening at a
lower level
or yeah like a cell instead of
multicellular organism
no i yeah i get that it's it's it's
anachronistic in in
in an important way um but
so so that maybe this helps to sharpen a
question
i mean the point of a paradigm is the
same as like what an individual frame
is right for an individual the point is
we we can never
we can't do algorithmic we can't do
arbitrary so we use constraints
and what we've been trying to do i mean
paradigm was one solution to that
because what you had was sets of soft
constraints you had
you know various paradigmatic
individuals you didn't have like a
recipe
right like always ask questions and it
has to have this syntactic formula
it was it was it was it was more
flexible was be like einstein
be like right right right and the
similarity function gives you
right the similarity function is right a
similar similarity to a prototype
is a way is a is a very powerful way of
sliding between
algorithmic and arbitrary right because
i can't just do do anything to be like
einstein
but it's not there's no algorithm right
because it's
it's similarity so what the question i'm
working towards is
right we have to get between algorithmic
and arbitrary
we need something like what paradigmatic
prototypes did for us
but what are those going to be like
right
one of the one of the advantages of
prototypes especially prototypical
individuals is we're sociocultural
beings and we have this
machinery of internalizing other people
that we can exact
for purposes of scientific inquiry i
know what it's like to be like einstein
even though i can't tell you
because i know what it's like to be like
my mom or my dad or my friends
right i know what that function is like
and so paradigms had
you see what i'm saying there's a reason
why they emerge
they seem like the
well i'm going to do this just to be
deliberately provocative they seem like
the final solution
uh to the problem of how do
you steer right how do you steer between
algorithmic and arbitrary
so if we can't do that anymore if right
if
so what what do we do who do we hold up
right so okay so let's let's reconnect
this so let's just wire wiring back into
the notion of the culture war and the
early sensibilities so the notion is
like part of the idea of the culture war
has this characteristic of almost having
a uh
a partisan sensibility and it's yes it's
a given point in culture space has a
but a war it's a sexual war right it's a
conflict and and part of the notion that
partisan sensibility is that
any given point in culture space is
endeavoring to identify that notion of
what is a good model like what is a good
person exactly exactly exactly um okay
so the question is something like it and
all right so you got kind of two
responses
one response is it's a competition of
prototypes that's that's how i would say
right it's a competition of prototypes
um
okay hold on and and in that context
it's and it's a competition between the
the context models that allow the answer
to what is a good prototype to emerge
right both are happening in really
interesting tension with each other
exactly that's what i'm going to say the
the thing about prototypes right is
um right is you don't
that's the whole point there's nothing
higher in terms of which you can compare
them
yeah okay so let's see um this also
feels very real time
um
yeah so if it if it sits at the level of
culture war
then it grounds out in energy it becomes
war right
um and the and that's not what we want
we want something other than that
right then that isn't and we can say we
don't want it for lots of reasons like
not least which is that i'm pretty sure
i can prove that that just ends with
everybody dying like there's not a yeah
necessary exactly exactly ultimately
we're trying to reduce suffering and
pain
yeah and keep it like below existential
or catastrophic
yeah um so let's see how does this work
it's actually it's it's it's very
interesting you just kind of shift it to
the individual level
can i say something that i've been doing
at the individual level yeah because
what i mean i i mean i because this
comes up with the people who have the
the the way purists like you should only
do buddhism
and i i propose like the ecology of
practices and i also propose the
plurality of sages
and the idea is i'm not gonna have right
the the single paradigmatic figure
anymore
what i have is a dynamic small world
network in which they're
in it so the thing in my mind is like
what the scientists do who are
moving the rovers around on mars right
what you do is you you have a bunch of
people
and and it's a it's a dynamic small
world network in which they're
constantly shifting
who has priority at that time and
there's no
right and and they and they do that sort
of in a dynamic fashion
yeah in terms of the content so for me
the idea is you know i'm an ecology of
functions
and then i develop an ecology of
practices
and then what i have is i don't have a
single paradigmatic individual
i have a pragmatic in the philosophical
sense of pragmatism
uh relationship between a plurality of
sages
and they're constantly shifting who gets
to be foregrounded who gets to be
backgrounded
the the temporary alliances they form
so it itself is never stable it's
constantly
but that doesn't mean that i have the
came up chaotic sense of normativity
instead what i seem to have is a fairly
continuous sense of normativity
but what it's constantly changing and
adapting and growing
that's what i've been trying to do yeah
i think this is right
um so let me say it back to you in a
different language i'm going to shift
actually shift modes because there's
something deeper there that i ca
i couldn't quite get to i could almost
get it and it's funny because like the
language the words that want to come out
of my mouth
i had to bite them off because they felt
like they were a little bit too
um not pithy but not powerful enough to
be
to contain what was being talked about
so i'm going to use um
uh tyson yonko portrays notion of
distinction from growth and increase
yep yep right and so what we're talking
about is is
we're solving for the problem of
increase and if you think about the
problem of increase in the very human
sense
um there's you know a small number of
basic questions
one question is uh you know
sage says who of all the possible
relationships
which are the ones that i will actually
attend to
um second
is in the context of a given sage a
given relationship what is the content
and so it was in the universe of
possibility of a given relationship
what is the subset of that possibility
that we collected that the relationship
will attend
and then finally the third is sort of
our capacity our relational capacity
what is the
the greatest uh gradient of which we are
capable of
as in the relationship yeah you you
up for a second i lost the last two
sentences you said um
you got a gradient and then you went
silent you're back yeah
i want to make sure because it looks
like there's a little bit of dropping
back and forth
just make sure am i back still
you're you're yes now you're back
okay yeah so the thing i'm seeing is
that that last move has to do with the
you know it's almost like the size of
the pipe or the the quality of capacity
of relationality
in the most in this deeply fundamental
sense that increases that the person
the versatility or the the possibility
of what could flow through the
relationship
right which of course is is an
individual capacity level
um it's funny in my mind i'm actually
seeing like this
you could imagine two musicians and like
the jazz metaphor
but you know the more skillful the
musician the more you can actually move
away from
any pre-existing constraints like we're
not doing jazz anymore
but doing meta jazz your background
is in like indian you know traditional
indian drumming and my background is in
um like
opera and yet we're so good at what we
do that we can actually begin the
process of just beginning with the
possibility of sound
and begin moving from there and just
create incredible stuff in the middle
right so the idea is like the
more this is this is the inverse of the
problem of paradigm difference
right you know obviously physics the
more the gradient or the more the delta
between two points the more the
possibilities that can flow through them
but the challenge of course you actually
have the capacity to enable a connection
and then allow that connection to be a
kind of a self-authorizing protocol like
you have to have some way of creating a
connection at all communication channel
and then the capacity
inside each node to expand the
communication channel bespoke to the
quality of the relationship and the
content that needs to flow through it
right that's the minimum viable content
at each node
is that as a basic capacity you know so
like you know you and i
interact the first thing we do is able
to establish just
you know pain remember the old dial-up
modems like we start making those funny
noises until
okay we now have a communications
channel and then what we do is we have a
capacity to to
from bespoke from just the fact of
communication at all
can begin the process of actually
building the size of building the
capacity of that channel to hold
more and more um it's really quite
interesting because if you think about
this really like this holistic
experience of like
it has to be joyful right is it a good
yeah like is it the question of who is
omnipresent
you know so i can't just kind of like
grab a hold of you and say fuck this now
we're gonna spend the next three years
building a channel
because maybe it's not the right who
there's eight billion people maybe
there's some other who that we should be
in relationship with so this is really
interesting like
meta sensibility of like is this the
right place to attend
that's interesting the the thing you
were doing with joy and the way you were
talking about this
i'm going to be talking to him soon it
reminds me of uh
jim carson's distinction between playing
finite and infinite games
cool good call jim carson's a great
person to bring it into this
exactly this moment because we're
talking about a lot of stuff that lives
proper at the level of the transcendent
like we're definitely
walking in those waters right now yeah
yeah yeah and uh
you know and i'm i'm actually you know
the religious case against belief who
has had a huge impact
on me i'm actually reading finite
infinite games right now because
i see dialectic as an infinite game that
is replacing
uh debate which is a finite game right
and so and and and the interesting
things
that what you're talking about there
right is because like
the meta jazz musician is
like the point of playing the music is
to also change the rules by which the
music is played
as you're playing it which is right
that's that's one of the defining
features
and that's what that's what i was trying
to get and you were doing it with like
you did with sort of a plurality of
genres and then the the
i'm trying to get something here
you you you have to get it such that
they can make a priority
for what cars calls and i i i he means
this differently than rory so
i don't want to confuse them but the
ability to continue right
the infinite game player wants the game
to continue
right that's the overarching normativity
right openness open versus closed
right the finite player wants it to come
uh to conclusion
so that they become entitled like in the
literal sense of being given a title
right right right and so there's a
i've got it going up literally a couple
of minutes so there there but there is
yeah so there's there's there it's
part of the change then is a change it's
got to be a fundamental change
in to understanding deeply
the normative requirements we've been
talking a lot about the cognitive
requirements
but the normative requirements on people
such that they're willing to play
infinite games you you and i have
reached the same exact point completely
granted
i was like puzzling all over that like
there's so many specific like that's it
the number of requirements such that
people are ready willing and able to
play
infinite games yeah exactly exactly
yeah if you're ready and willing then
you're in the educational mode
great let us begin to build in you the
capacity to durably
operate under these normative
constraints when you're actually now
ready willing and able welcome to
infinite game space
so what has to come to the fore and this
is something
you know you and i have been emphasizing
and this i think is in
uh jim's work um
is right the the the mechanisms of
self-create
correction have to be given like they
they're given much more priority
yeah right um that's really interesting
so this this this could dovetail back
maybe we can pick this up next time
because
this dovetails back with this attempt to
get at this notion that i've been
jocking around with two of meta
rationality in which
right instead of closing to a conclusion
right you're constantly trying to
improve your capacity for
self-correction
so that you can constantly adjust the
normativity
right for playing the infinite game yeah
yeah all right
okay my friend we'll be talking again
soon you and you and i and greg
thank you very much as always this is
wonderful yeah this is really good
i want to pick this up again i think we
must
okay take care bye bye